(Level 1 Demon Lord and One Room Hero)
《Lv1魔王與獨居廢勇者》
ROYAL MARTIAL ARTS TOURNAMENT
(王國武道會)
(Episode 5: With Your Majesty!) Opponent is a member of the Kingdom's Knights
(#5 與陛下!) 對手是王國騎士團團員
Leo.
雷奧
D GROUP, SECOND MATCH
(D組第二場)
That guy named Leo is really strong,
那個叫雷奧的傢伙真強
he's way more powerful than the others.
只有他遠比其他人厲害得多
Of course.
那當然
With this momentum, you'll definitely win the championship.
照這股氣勢獲勝吧
We're counting on you, Leo.
拜託囉 雷奧
Only you are worthy to be a hero.
只有你有資格當勇者
He just got lucky, I guess.
只是歪打正著吧
He's got some skills.
挺有一手的嘛
Even you might…
就算是你 恐怕也…
Are you going out?
你要出門嗎
I should go for a walk since I have been staying home.
最近都窩在家裡 偶爾也想出去走走
What are you doing?
幹嘛
Actually…
其實…
I want to go with you too.
朕也想一起去
Where are we going?
要去哪裡
I was just planning on walking around and then going home,
我本來打算晃一下就回去
I don't have a specific place in mind.
沒有特別想去的地方
Then let's go shopping for clothes.
那就去買衣服吧
What do you think of this outfit?
你覺得這件怎麼樣
Is this outfit suitable for me? What do you think?
適不適合朕 你說呢
Not bad.
不錯啊
But…
可是…
I want to find something that enhances my majesty even more.
想找一件更能襯托朕的威嚴的
How about this one then?
不然這件呢
That's fine, just buy that one.
可以啦 就買那件吧
Will I look good wearing this?
這件穿起來會好看嗎
Are you done yet…
夠了沒
By the way…
話說…
You're a guy, right?
你是男的吧
It doesn't really matter
這種事情
if I'm a guy or a girl.
是男是女都沒關係吧
If you have time, would you like to try it on?
有空的話 要不要試穿看看呢
No need for formalities, please show me the way.
免禮 幫朕帶路
Don't talk to the salesperson in that tone of voice.
不要用那種語氣跟店員講話
Oh right,
對了
we need to buy some children's clothes too.
還要買幾件童裝
I see, that's great news.
原來是這樣嗎 真不錯
It's not like that, we just…
不是那樣 我們…
You made the salesperson misunderstand, just stop talking.
你害店員誤會了啦 別說了
I'm exhausted.
累死我了
You're so pathetic, can you even be called a hero?
太散漫了吧 你這樣還算是勇者嗎
Max, keep it up.
麥克斯 加油
We can go home today after we take down this place.
只要攻下這裡 今天就能回去了
What do you want to eat? I'll cook anything for you.
你想吃什麼 朕都煮給你吃
Let me think…
我想一下…
Please try our delicious mini sausages, they're really tasty.
提供小香腸試吃 很好吃喔
Bouncy and juicy. Let's buy some.
彈牙多汁 買一些吧
Thank you for your patronage. Oh my, could you be…
謝謝惠顧 什麼 難道說…
You're Mr. Max, right?
您是麥克斯先生吧
Uh, yes.
呃 對
-Wow, what a coincidence. -You're recognized again. Great.
-好棒喔 居然會在這裡巧遇 -又有人認出你 太好了
-Shut up.
-吵死了
Is this your girlfriend? She's so beautiful.
是你的女朋友嗎 好漂亮啊
You're too kind.
沒有那麼誇張啦
Could I shake your hand, Mr. Hero?
請問可以跟我握個手嗎 勇者大人
No one calls me a hero anymore.
現在已經沒人會叫我勇者了
I never thought I'd run into you in a place like this.
真沒想到會在這種地方碰到你
It's an unexpected gain.
算是意外的收穫
You are…
妳是…
I was just thinking your hands are quite rough.
正想說妳的手相當粗糙
You're as rude as ever when it comes to women.
你還是一如往常 對女性這麼失禮
I was just about to take a break.
我正好要去休息
Would you like to join me downstairs for a chat?
要不要去樓下小聊一下
What if I refuse?
如果我拒絕呢
Neither of us wants to make a scene, right?
我們彼此都不想把事情鬧大吧
I'm afraid your girlfriend will have to wait.
只能請女朋友稍等了 知道嗎
Max.
麥克斯
Just pretend to be a normal girl for now.
你先裝成普通的女生
I need to talk to her about something, you go back first.
我要跟她談一些事 妳先回去
What's going on?
怎麼回事
Who is this woman anyway?
這個女的到底是什麼來頭
THE TRUE FACE OF THE REPUBLIC GAMMA IS TEAR-JERKING I'M A TERRORIST. NO WAY
(剛瑪共和國的真實樣貌令人泛淚) (我是恐怖分子 騙人的吧)
She's Leo's subordinate.
她是雷奧的部下
She's probably a member of the Republic Gamma now.
現在應該是剛瑪共和國的成員
Wait, Max. Who is that woman?
等等 麥克斯 那個女人是誰
Stop right there.
給我站住
That girlfriend seems way better than the previous ones.
那個女朋友感覺比前幾任好多了
She's not my girlfriend.
她才不是我女朋友
But is it okay?
不過沒問題嗎
That girl seems quite young.
那女孩看起來年紀挺小的呢
I was about to ask you the same thing.
我才想問妳有沒有問題
What are you doing in a place like this?
妳跑來這種地方做什麼
Well…
算是…
Spying, I guess?
間諜活動
Is she Leo's subordinate? That's very concerning.
雷奧的部下嗎 真令人在意
Although he told me to go home first…
雖然他叫朕先回家…
I'd better check the situation.
還是去看一下狀況好了
Will he encounter any danger?
他會不會碰到什麼危險
Or is he doing something else dangerous?
莫非在做 另一種意義上的危險的事
Un-Unforgivable.
不…不可原諒
Sorry.
不好意思
You are Max's companion, right?
妳是麥克斯的同伴吧
Yes.
對啊
I'll take you to Max. Follow me.
我帶妳去找麥克斯 跟我來
You don't have to come if you don't want to.
不想來也可以
But you might never see Max again.
不過 到時妳就會和麥克斯永別了
Will you lead the way for me? Thank you.
你要幫人家帶路嗎 謝謝
Carry this for me.
東西給你拿
Here you go.
給你
When did we last meet?
上一次見面是幾年前啊
Let me think.
我想想
It was two years before your rebellion. So almost five years.
是你們謀反的兩年前 所以快要五年了
Yeah, you look older, Max.
對耶 你老了呢 麥克斯
You see, I haven't aged at all.
我則是完全沒老喔
After all, I exercise regularly, and my hands have become rough.
畢竟我勤做鍛鍊 手都變粗糙了
Is the captain doing well?
團長過得還好嗎
He's still as energetic as ever.
他還是一樣精神充沛
You really do care.
你果然會在意
Captain Leo also thinks of you often.
雷奧團長也同樣惦記著你
He sometimes says,
有事沒事就說
"I wonder if Max is doing well. I wonder what he's doing now."
"麥克斯過得好不好" "他現在在做什麼"
I'm just living the way you see me now.
就是妳看到的這副拙樣
You're from the Republic Gamma, right?
你是剛瑪共和國的人吧
Yes.
對
So you're a terrorist, huh? How scary.
所以你是恐怖分子囉 真可怕
We're not terrorists.
我們才不是恐怖分子
Listen, it's all the kingdom's fault.
聽好了 一切都是王國的錯
You're going to break the egg like that.
這樣會撞破雞蛋
Do you know how the captain feels being exiled to that barren land?
知道團長被放逐到 那片荒蕪之地的感受嗎
Do you know how much effort we put in to develop that land?
知道我們耗費多少心力 開闢那塊土地嗎
But as soon as they found magic ore there, those guys just…
然而一發現那裡有魔礦石 那群傢伙就…
Sorry, don't be rude to me.
對不起 不要對人家動粗
So you want Max to join you in your battle against the kingdom?
所以你們想拉攏麥克斯 對抗王國
You think we're stupid, don't you?
這麼做很蠢吧
What is the point of having another retired old man,
不管他打倒了魔王還是怎樣
whether he defeated Demon Lord or not?
多了一個退休大叔 又有什麼幫助
But everyone is clamoring to find Max.
不過大家都吵著要找麥克斯
I just have to help reluctantly.
我只好勉為其難來幫忙
In my own way.
以我自己的方式
What?
什麼嘛
What's with the swagger, you idiot?
跩什麼跩 你這個蠢貨
If you were to face off against Max, you'd be knocked out in two seconds.
你這種貨色敢挑釁麥克斯 兩秒就會被打飛
That is something to be excited about.
那還真是令人期待
Oh, Fred invited you, huh?
是嗎 弗雷德邀你去
How did you respond?
那你怎麼回答
I rejected it. I don't want to get involved in trouble.
我拒絕了 不想被捲進麻煩
Great.
太好了
So, do you want to get me involved in trouble too?
所以呢 妳也想把我捲進麻煩嗎
I am on the fence about it.
有一半是這麼打算
I have something for you.
想給你一個東西
REPUBLIC GAMMA This is a ship ticket to the Republic Gamma.
(剛瑪共和國) 是前往剛瑪共和國的船票
It stops at Tratigo on the way.
中途停靠多拉齊格
With this ticket, even people from the kingdom can safely reach there.
只要憑那個 王國的人也能順利來我們這裡
You really didn't bring me anything good. Tratigo, huh?
果然不是什麼好事 多拉齊格嗎
The people there are cunning too, right?
那個地方也是華而不實吧
Yes.
是啊
But they are our important business partners.
不過是我們重要的商業夥伴
To be honest, I really hope you can join us.
坦白說 我是真心希望你能加入
If you're willing, come visit us.
願意的話再過來玩玩吧
The captain will be very happy.
團長一定會很開心
I'll think about it.
我再考慮看看
Big sister, you're too naive.
大姐妳太天真了
Giving him that kind of thing is pointless.
給他那種東西也沒有意義
Do you want to watch helplessly as the hero we finally found leaves us?
難道要眼睜睜地看著 好不容易找到的勇者離開嗎
Will.
威爾
Max, save me.
麥克斯 救救人家
This guy is scary.
這個人好可怕
What are you doing, Will?
你在幹什麼 威爾
Let the girl go immediately.
立刻放開那個女孩
-Save me -Sister, sometimes we need to be tough.
-來救我… -大姐 有時需要使出強硬手段
-Save me… -Do you think he'll come with just that piece of paper?
-以為給他那種紙片 他就會來嗎
See, all we have to do is this and he'll have to give in.
看吧 只要這麼做 他也不得不屈服了
You know.
我說你啊
Isn't it terroristic to take hostages
抓人質逼對方服從
to force someone to do something?
不就是恐怖分子的行為嗎
Do you want to embarrass the captain?
難道你想害團長丟盡顏面嗎
Yeah, Big Sister is right.
對啊 大姐說得沒錯
Don't call me Big Sister.
不准叫我大姐
In the kingdom, you can only get distorted
在王國得不到 剛瑪共和國的正確資訊
and false information about the Republic Gamma.
盡是扭曲事實的假消息
I kindly invite you and your girlfriend to visit.
我是好心招待你跟女朋友來一趟
You'll definitely like it.
你肯定會喜歡
It's better than this corrupt country.
總比這個腐敗的國家好
My girlfriend?
女朋友
Where is this girlfriend of mine you mentioned?
你說的女朋友在哪裡啊
I don't see her.
我怎麼沒看到
Max, don't you care about my life and death?
麥克斯 你不管朕…我的死活了嗎
Save me, you fool! Useless, you sponge off women.
快來救我 你這個笨蛋 廢物 小白臉
-So you sponge off women, huh? -Sponge off women…useless.
-原來你是小白臉嗎 -小白臉…沒出息的小白臉
I've always wanted to chat with the hero face-to-face.
虧我一直想跟勇者當面談談
Absolutely disappointed.
簡直失望透頂
Your girlfriend was captured, and you don't even have the courage to fight.
女朋友被抓了 卻連打一場的膽量都沒有
Taking him to see the captain will only disappoint the captain.
帶去見團長 只會害他失望
Will, stop it.
威爾 別再說了
That's right. There's no point in having an old man like me join.
沒錯 找我這種大叔加入也沒意義
Waste of my time.
浪費一堆時間
Even if you refuse,
就算你拒絕
now that you know of our existence, we can't just let you go easily.
既然知道了我們的存在 那可不能輕易放你們回去
Ridiculous.
有夠亂來
You guys approached me first.
是你們主動纏上來的
Have you had enough? Shut up and come with us.
夠了沒 就叫你閉嘴乖乖跟我們走
-Or else… -Ouch!
-不然的話… -好痛
That's better, isn't it?
這樣比較好吧
If I resist, my true identity might be exposed.
要是朕抵抗 搞不好會曝露真身
It's more disadvantageous for you.
反而對你比較不利
After all, don't let him catch you so easily. Fool.
不要隨便被他抓住好嗎 傻瓜
I'm truly sorry, Max.
真的很抱歉 麥克斯
He was just a kid ten years ago.
他十年前還是個小孩子
He doesn't fully understand your achievements.
不太瞭解你的事蹟
I also want to apologize for scaring you.
也要跟妳說聲抱歉 嚇到妳了
He's really rude, isn't he?
真是沒禮貌
He doesn't know how formidable Max is. How outdated!
居然不知道麥克斯多麼威猛 太落伍了吧
Will.
威爾
I was wrong. I'm very sorry, Mr. Max.
是我錯了 非常抱歉 麥克斯先生
It's good that you know to reflect.
知道反省就好
Don't cause trouble for Leo.
別給雷奧添麻煩
Alright.
好的
We're going back to the Republic.
我們要回共和國了
We were planning to retreat anyway.
反正本來就打算撤退了
Besides, I might report you guys to Fred.
而且我搞不好會向弗雷德舉發你們
That's what I'm saying.
就是說啊
So we need to leave quickly before that.
所以要在那之前趕快閃人
Take care.
小心安全
Thanks.
謝謝
Goodbye.
再見囉
Unbelievable.
真是的
It's rare that we go out shopping and they dare to interrupt us.
難得出門採購 竟敢打斷我們
I'm exhausted.
真是累死我了
Don't you want to join the Republic Gamma?
你不會想要加入剛瑪共和國嗎
Not at all. Spare me.
才不會呢 饒了我吧
If you want to go to the Republic,
如果你想去共和國
I can go with you.
朕也可以陪你去喔
We can overthrow the corrupt system,
推翻腐敗的體制
and build a new country with Leo.
與雷奧一起建立新國家
That's quite the hero-like thing to do.
這樣也挺有勇者風範的啊
In that case, we'll have to wage war against Fred.
那樣的話 就要和弗雷德開戰了
It's fine. Let's get back quickly.
沒事 趕快回去吧
Are your hands okay? We're almost there.
你的手還好嗎 快要到了
Sorry, Big Sister.
對不起 大姐
Seahorse.
海馬號
Joe.
喬
Big Sister, long time no see.
大姐 好久沒看到妳
Will is here too.
威爾也在啊
We're back.
我們回來了
Is Captain Leo on the ship?
雷奧團長該不會在船上吧
No, he's not here right now.
不 現在剛好不在
Not here right now?
現在不在
Perfect timing. Look.
時機正好 妳看
Awesome!
太棒啦
Captain.
團長
He's still as reckless as ever.
他還是一樣亂來
Both of you,
你們兩個
just in time. Get ready for dinner.
來得正好 準備開飯
TRATIGO, REPUBLIC GAMMA
(多拉齊格 剛瑪共和國)
Is this the ticket that woman gave you? A ship ticket to the Gamma Republic?
這是那女人給你的 往剛瑪共和國的船票嗎
Why did you take a picture?
為什麼要拍照
Because you can't buy this in the kingdom.
因為這東西在王國買不到
AIRSHIP TICKET
(飛船船票)
I'm going to sell it online.
我打算放到網路上賣掉
You're too poor, aren't you?
有夠吝嗇
Do you have a problem with that?
有意見嗎
This is my ticket. How I use it is my freedom.
這是給我的 要怎麼使用是我的自由吧
You got a ticket, don't you want to see the Republic?
難得收到票 不去共和國看看嗎
Come on.
拜託
It's a well-known terrorist territory.
那裡是公認的恐怖分子地盤
It's dangerous as hell. Who wants to go there?
危險死了 誰要去啊
You might never return.
搞不好會一去不回
It's even more dangerous to resell tickets to such a place.
轉賣那種地方的船票 反而更危險吧
Right.
對了
Teleportal.
"轉移路標"
It seems my power has recovered quite a bit.
看來朕的力量恢復了不少
I've set the return point for the teleportation spell inside this closet.
朕已經把傳送咒語的返回場所 設在這個壁櫥裡了
If something happens on our journey, we can return here.
萬一在旅途中出狀況 也能立刻回到這裡
Don't set up weird stuff in my closet!
不要在別人家壁櫥設置怪東西
Are you looking for me?
您找我嗎
Zenia, we'll be out for about two days.
潔妮亞 我們要外出兩天左右
During this time, please take care of things for us…
在這段期間要麻煩妳…
Alright, I got it. Leave it to me.
好 我明白了 請包在我身上
I didn't say I was going.
我又沒說要去
Can't you go by yourself, Your Majesty?
能不能請您自己去呢 陛下
Max,
麥克斯
why don't you understand my feelings?
為什麼你就是不懂朕的心情
Don't you want to go out and have fun with me?
你這麼不想跟朕一起出去玩嗎
No, I just…
不 我只是…
You finally woke up, Max.
你終於清醒過來啦 麥克斯
You have nowhere to run now.
已經無處可逃了
Damn it, I've been tricked.
可惡 被擺了一道
Was it necessary to go this far?
有必要做到這個地步嗎
You could have easily deflected
那種程度的幻惑術
a deception spell of that level ten years ago.
十年前的你肯定能輕易彈開吧
Seems like you've become complacent in peace.
看來是安於和平 太大意囉
I'm going to take revenge.
你給我記住
Max, there's one more thing.
麥克斯 還有一件事
This time, we're on a reconnaissance mission.
這次終究是去偵察的
To plan for the future,
為了今後做打算
we must understand the situation in the Republic Gamma.
我們必須瞭解剛瑪共和國的情勢
We're not going there for fun, understand?
並不是去玩的 知道嗎
You say that, but you're dressed in a full travel outfit.
嘴上那麼說 卻穿了整套出遊裝扮
Max, look.
麥克斯 你看
The vast ocean before us.
眼前這一望無際的大海
The airship is amazing.
飛空船真是太棒了
BESKER KINGDOM, SERGENDINE TRATIGO, TRATIGO INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT
(貝斯卡王國 賽爾根達) (多拉齊格 多拉齊格國際機場)
REPUBLIC GAMMA
(剛瑪共和國)
We're approaching the Republic Gamma.
即將抵達剛瑪共和國
Passengers on the deck, please return to the cabin.
請甲板上的乘客回到客艙
With the exception of that woman, many of Leo's subordinates recognize me.
除了那個女人 不少雷奧的部下也認得出我
If they see us, we'll be in trouble.
要是被他們看見 那就麻煩了
Don't worry, I never make mistakes.
放心吧 朕做事萬無一失
Wear this.
戴上這個吧
Not bad, it suits you. Super cool.
不錯啊 很適合你 超帥的
Do you want me to put you back to sleep for another ten years?
要不要讓你再睡個十年
WELCOME TO THE REPUBLIC GAMMA
(歡迎來到剛瑪共和國)
Look, there's smoke over there.
快看 在冒煙
Could it be a conflict?
莫非是爆發衝突了
No, it seems to be a hot spring.
不 看來是溫泉
There's a hot spring flowing through this street.
街道上有溫泉流過啊
In my hometown, there are places where lava flows.
在朕的家鄉 有些地方會流岩漿
It's nostalgic.
真令人懷念
Hi, you two…
來…兩位…
Welcome to try the hot spring buns.
歡迎試吃溫泉饅頭
Give it a try, go ahead and eat.
吃吃看吧 快點吃吃看…
Delicious.
好好吃
Here, eat more. More, more.
來 多吃點喔 再吃再吃
Here, have some tea.
來 喝杯茶
It's hot.
好燙
Damn old lady.
臭老太婆
This is a nice place.
這是個好地方啊
It doesn't look like a terrorist country at all.
怎麼看都不像恐怖主義國家
At the very least, a tourist stop should be well-presented.
觀光客會來的大門口 至少要包裝得像樣點吧
This means they have the means to raise so much funding.
這表示有辦法籌措這種程度的資金
Do you really think the Republic Gamma is an evil force?
你果然認為剛瑪共和國是惡勢力嗎
It's not about good or evil.
這無關善惡
No matter what the inside story is,
不管有什麼內情
the very existence of this place is enough to cause disputes.
這個地方的存在本身 就是引起紛爭的導火線
For the people of the kingdom, this place only brings them trouble, that's all.
對王國的人來說只會徒增困擾 只是這樣罷了
You talking about serious issues with that expression makes it even funnier.
用那張臉講嚴肅的話題 反而更滑稽了
What do you think?
那你又是怎麼想的
Me?
朕嗎
Why should you, a demon, interfere in the petty disputes among humans?
你這個魔族何必插手 人類之間的無聊糾紛
I…
朕…對你們…
I am just waiting for you humans to screw up and exploit the situation.
朕只是想等你們人類兩敗俱傷 趁機漁翁得利
This is also to allow our fellow demons to invade the human realm again.
這也是為了讓 我等魔之眷屬再次侵略人界
If you could join Leo or Fred and fight each other, that would be even better.
要是你能加入雷奧或弗雷德 自相殘殺 那就更好了
I'm sorry I can't meet your expectations, Your Majesty.
抱歉無法回應您的期待 陛下
It's starting…
開始了…
Is that Captain Leo?
他就是雷奧團長嗎
What, Leo's here?
什麼 雷奧來了嗎
With so many people gathered, what's he going to do?
聚集這麼多人 是要做什麼
He will probably give a speech from up high.
八成是要高高在上發表演說吧
Alright, let's go.
好 來吧
Yay!
嘿唷…
Come on, come on!
再來再來…
What's he doing?
他在做什麼
Don't ask me.
不要問我
That's called "mixing the soup."
那叫做"揉湯"
Old lady.
老太婆
Because the hot springs are too hot to bathe in directly,
因為直接入浴會太燙
GAMMA but adding water to the hot springs will dilute the components.
(剛瑪) 但是加水會稀釋成分
So you have to mix it like that
所以要像那樣攪拌
GAMMA to bring the temperature of the hot springs down to a suitable level.
(剛瑪) 讓溫泉降至適合的溫度
I see.
原來如此
But that man seems to enjoy the hot springs before they cool down.
但那個人倒是很享受降溫前的溫泉
So hot.
超燙
That's the heroic figure of the leader of the Republic Gamma.
那就是剛瑪共和國首領的英姿
It looks like he's just playing.
看起來只是在玩鬧
Alright, this should be about right.
好 這樣就差不多了
Everyone!
各位
Thank you very much! Enjoy the hot springs!
非常感謝 好好享受溫泉吧
He's quite spirited, that's great.
挺有精神的嘛 太好了
Yeah.
是啊
He's still the same.
他還是老樣子
It's not surprising who wins.
誰獲勝都不奇怪
Yeah, this battle is bound to be exciting.
是啊 這一戰肯定很精彩
Do you really understand the meaning of this martial arts tournament?
你真的明白這場武道會的意義嗎
I do.
我明白
Can you fight the demons with a determination to die?
你能抱著必死決心與魔族交戰嗎
I can.
可以
Begin.
開始
Come on, Leo.
加油 雷奧
Defeat that outsider.
打敗那個門外漢
Leo.
雷奧